Finding aid for Association for Asian Studies records, 1947-1988
Bentley Historical Library
- Regional Councils
  - South/Asia Regional Council (SARC), 1955-1978
    - Topical Files, 1968-1979
      - University Curricula
        - Washington (University of) (Box 34)
        - Wisconsin (University of) (Box 34)
      - Visual Resource Committee, 1969 (Box 34)
      - Workshop, Ann Arbor, 1978 (Box 35)
    - Studies Groups and Committees, 1969-1977
      - Afghanistan Committee
        - Bibliographic proposal, 1975-1976 (Box 35)
        - Correspondence and reports, 1973-1976 (Box 35)
      - Bangladesh Committee, 1972-1976 (Box 35)
      - Institutional Liaison Committee
        - 1969-1971 (Box 35)
        - 1972-1973 (Box 35)
        - 1974-1975 (Box 35)
        - 1976 (Box 35)
        - Correspondence and reports
          - 1970-1977 (scattered) (Box 35)
          - 1977 (Box 35)
      - India Committee Scattered materials (Box 35)
      - Language and Literature Development Committee
        - 1969-1976 (Box 35)
        - 1976-1977 (Box 35)
        - Conference on "Minor" S.A. Language Teaching, 1974 (Box 35)
        - Conference on the Verb in India, 1974 (Box 35)
      - Correspondence and reports, 1974-1978 (Box 35)
      - Preparation of an Individualized Teaching system for South Asia Language
        - General, 1972 (Box 35)
        - Report, 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 35)
      - Nepal Committee
        - 1973-1977 (scattered) (Box 35)
        - Correspondence and reports, 1972-1974 (Box 35)
        - Newsletter, 1972-1978 (Box 35)
      - Pakistan Committee
        - Annual Report
          - 1972-1973 (Box 35)
          - 1974 (Box 35)
          - 1975 (Box 35)
          - 1976 (Box 35)
        - Committee mailing, 1970-1971 (Box 35)
        - Committee reports, 1972 (Box 35)
        - Conference
          - 1971 (Box 35)
          - 1973 (Box 35)
        - Minutes, 1971 (Box 35)
        - Political material, 1971 (Box 35)
        - Report, 1972 (Box 36)
        - Statement of Purpose, 1972 (Box 36)
        - Symposium proposal, 1973 (Box 36)
      - Sri Lanka Committee
        - Annual Report, 1976 (Box 36)
        - Correspondence and reports
          - 1975 (Box 36)
          - Scattered (Box 36)
        - Report and request, 1972-1973 (Box 36)
        - Report to SARC and AAS (Box 36)
        - Workshop, 1976 (Box 36)
    - Regional Council Affiliates, 1968-1980
      - Afghanistan Studies Association
        - Correspondence and reports, 1971-1977 (Box 36)
        - Newsletter, 1973-1976 (Box 36)
      - Bengal Studies Group
        - 1969-1981 (Box 36)
        - Conferences on Bengal
          - 1968 (Box 36)
          - 1970 (Box 36)
          - 1971 (Box 36)
          - 1972 (Box 36)
          - 1973 (Box 36)
          - 1974 (Box 36)
          - 1975 (Box 36)
          - 1976 (Box 36)
          - 1977 (Box 36)
        - Conference on Religion in South India, 1972-1977 (Box 36)
      - Maharashtra Sub-committee, 1969-1980 (Box 36)
      - Nepal Studies Committee
        - 1970-1980 (Box 36)
        - Newsletter (Bulletin), 1972-1976; 1980 (Box 36)
      - Research Committee on the Punjab, 1969-1976 (Box 36)
      - Society for Asian Comparative philosophy, 1973-1979 (Box 36)
      - Society for South India Studies, 1969-1980
        - General (Box 36)
        - Newsletter, 1973-1980 (scattered) (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Committee on South Asia Libraries and Documentation, 1969-1974; 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Papers presented at the CONSALD Conference, 1974; 2 folders (Box 47)
      - Southeast Asia Committee, 1962; 1965; 1966-1969 (Box 47)
  - Southeast Asia Regional Council (SEARC), 1968-1982
    Southeast Asia Regional Council (SEARC) files are particularly notable for detailed information regarding the interaction of the Council with the Ford Foundation. Also of interest are the records of the Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group (SEADAG), the Vietnam Studies Coordinating Group, which served as a focal point for discussion of U.S. foreign policy during the Vietnam war, and the Committee on Research Materials on Southeast Asia (CORMOSEA).
    - Topical Files, 1968-1981
      - AAS Nominating Committee, 1978 (Box 36)
      - AAS/ISAC Meeting, 1972 (Box 36)
      - Activities Reports, 1968-1972 (some gaps); 5 folders (Box 36)
      - Benda Memorial, 1971-1977 (Box 36)
      - Budget, 1970-1974 (Box 36)
      - Budget and proposal to Ford, 1971-1974 (Box 36)
      - Center Directors
        - Meetings, 1971-1972; 2 folders (Box 36)
        - Reception, 1971 (Box 36)
      - Committee on Constitutional Revision, 1975 (Box 36)
      - Correspondence and Summary reports, 1970-1974 (Box 37)
      - Council Meetings
        - 1970 (Box 37)
        - 1971
          - Washington (February) (Box 37)
          - Washington (March) (Box 37)
          - New York (May) (Box 37)
          - Washington (September) (Box 37)
        - 1972
          - San Francisco (Box 37)
          - New York (Box 37)
        - 1973
          - Ann Arbor (Box 37)
          - Chicago (Box 37)
        - 1974 (Box 37)
        - 1975 (Box 37)
        - 1976 (Box 37)
        - 1977 (Box 37)
      - Current acquisitions problems, 1969 (Box 37)
      - Documents (Box 37)
      - Executive Committee Meeting
        - 1970-1972 (Box 37)
        - 1973 (Box 37)
      - Ford Foundation
        - 1971-Spring 1972 (Box 37)
        - Fall 1972 (Box 37)
        - Announcement, 1971 (Box 37)
        - Brief report on Ford Grant 710-05598, May 1975 (Box 37)
        - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 37)
        - Fellowship Awards
          - 1970 (Box 37)
          - 1971 (Box 37)
          - 1971-Spring 1972 (Box 37)
          - 1974 (Box 37)
        - Fellowship Program
          - 1974 (Box 37)
          - Bangkok, 1975 (Box 37)
        - Final Report to, March 1974 (Box 37)
        - Funds, 1977 (Box 37)
        - Future Ford, 1977 (Box 37)
        - Grant, 1974-1975 (Box 37)
        - Indonesia, 1976 (Box 37)
        - Project Funding, 1971 (Box 37)
        - Proposal, 1974-1977 (Box 37)
        - Refugees, 1975 (Box 37)
        - Report, 1973-1974 (Box 37)
        - Report, 1975 (Box 37)
        - Research Committee Meeting, 1972 (Box 37)
        - Research Funding Report, 1969 (Box 37)
        - SEARC Report to Ford Foundation
          - 1974 (Box 37)
          - 1977 (Box 37)
        - Tabulations, FSEAFP, 1971-1973 (Box 37)
        - Twelve Point Criteria (Box 37)
      - International Congress of Orientalists, Canberra, January, 1971 (Box 37)
      - Interuniversity Southeast Asia Committee
        - AAS-ISAC Constitutional Relations, 1970 (Box 37)
        - AAS Meeting, 1970 (Box 37)
        - Basic Documents, 1968 (Box 37)
        - Budget and summary, 1970-1971 (Box 37)
        - Correspondence
          - 1968 (Box 37)
          - 1969 (Box 37)
        - Council meeting, 1969 (Box 38)
        - Draft Statement of purpose, 1969 (Box 38)
        - Elections, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 38)
        - Executive Committee meetings
          - 1969 (Box 38)
            (Chicago)
          - 1969 (Box 38)
            (Detroit)
          - 1970 (Box 38)
        - Finances
          - 1970-1971 (Box 38)
          - Scattered (Box 38)
        - Ford Foundations, 1968 (Box 38)
        - Golay Report, 1968 (Box 38)
        - Government Liaison
          - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 38)
          - Finances, 1969-1970 (Box 38)
          - Minutes, 1969 (Box 38)
          - Reports, 1969-1972 (Box 38)
          - Wriggins, Howard (chairman), 1969 (Box 38)
        - International Liaison: Libraries in Southeast Asia (Box 38)
        - ISAC/SEARC, 1968-1970 (Box 38)
        - ISAC and the proposed AAS constitutional changes, 1969 (Box 38)
        - Joint Meeting of SEARC and Language Resources Committee, 1974 (Box 38)
        - Journal of Asian Studies, 1971-1978 (Box 38)
        - Meetings, 1968-1969; 3 folders (Box 38)
        - Proposal (Ford Foundation), 1968 (Box 38)
        - Rights and responsibility statement, 1971 (Box 38)
        - Subcommittee on Floating Centers (Vietnam), 1968-1969 (Box 38)
        - Survey to Dissolve ISAC, 1973 (Box 38)
        - Tillman Book, 1970-1971 (Box 38)
        - U.S. Centers and Foreign Centers (Box 38)
        - Working notes and proposals for organization, 1968 (Box 38)
      - Maryanov report, 1972 (Box 38)
      - Materials for new funding proposal, 1972-1974 (Box 38)
      - Minutes and reports, 1972-1974 (Box 38)
      - Monograph Series Proposal, 1971 (Box 38)
      - NEH Material (Box 38)
      - Newsletters, 1971-1974 (Box 38)
      - Regional Conference Support, 1975-1978 (Box 38)
      - Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group
        - Correspondence and reports, 1970-1971 (scattered) (Box 38)
        - Program Committee: Correspondence, 1972-1973 (scattered) (Box 38)
        - Public Relations, Brackman, 1971 (Box 38)
        - Research Funds: Survey, 1968 (Box 38)
        - Research Materials, 1968 (Box 38)
      - SEARC Annual Reports, 1972-1975; 3 folders (Box 38)
      - SEARC By-Laws:, 1967-1973 (scattered) (Box 38)
      - SEARC Coordinator Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 38)
      - SEARC Draft Proposal, 1974 (Box 38)
      - SEARC Meeting, March 1975 (Box 38)
      - SEARC Publications (misc.) (Box 38)
      - Social Science Research Council Correspondence, 1975 (Box 39)
      - Southeast Asia area studies: A memorandum by Lucian Pye, 1967 (Box 39)
    - Studies Groups and Committees, 1969-1982
      - Education and Professional Development
        - Committee (Box 39)
        - Correspondence
          - 1973 (Box 39)
          - 1975-1976 (Box 39)
        - Foreign Student Advisor University of Minnesota, Paul Pederson, 1973-1975 (Box 39)
      - Language Resources Committee
        - Annual Reports, 1972-1975 (Box 39)
        - Committee meetings
          - 1974 (Box 39)
          - 1976 (Box 39)
        - Correspondence, 1969-1973; 4 folders (Box 39)
        - Language Survey, 1972-1974; 2 folders (Box 39)
        - Memo on Language Institutes, 1975 (Box 39)
        - Summer intensive program, 1971 (Box 39)
      - Malaysia-Singapore-Brunei Studies Group
        - Annual Reports (Box 39)
        - Conference report, 1971 (Box 39)
        - Correspondence and reports (scattered) (Box 39)
        - Newsletter (Berita)
          - 1975-1978 (Box 39)
          - 1978-1981 (Box 39)
        - Burma Study Group
          - Correspondence and reports, 1971-1973 (Box 39)
          - Funding requests, 1972 (Box 39)
          - Newsletters, 1973-1974 (Box 39)
          - Reports, 1973-1976 (Box 39)
        - Committee on research materials on Southeast Asia (CORMOSEA)
          - Annual Reports, 1970; 1972-1973 (Box 39)
          - Budgets and reports, 1973-1974 (Box 39)
          - Correspondence, 1968-1977; 7 folders (Box 39)
          - Finances, 1969-1972; 2 folders (Box 39)
          - History to, 1971 (Box 39)
          - Library of Congress, 1975-1976 (Box 39)
          - Meetings
            - 1969 (Box 39)
            - 1970-1971 (Box 40)
            - 1974 (Box 40)
            - 1976 (Box 40)
            - 1979 (Box 40)
          - Minutes, 1970-1982 (Box 40)
          - NEH Grant for "Southeast Asia Research Tools,", 1976-1977 (Box 40)
          - Newsletter Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 40)
          - Newsletter copies, 1969-1977; 4 folders (Box 40)
          - Southeast Asia microforms (SEAM) Correspondence (scattered) (Box 40)
      - Indonesia Studies Group
        - Ad Hoc Meeting (New York), 1973 (Box 40)
        - Conferences
          - July 1973 (Box 40)
            (Madison)
          - 1976-1980 (Box 40)
        - Correspondence
          - 1973-1974 (Box 40)
          - 1975-1977 (Box 40)
        - Indonesia Questionnaire, Spring 1973 (Box 40)
        - Newsletter: Antarakha, (Kabap Angin), 1974-1982 (Box 40)
        - Report and Recommendations to SKARC, undated (Box 40)
        - Summer Conferences (Box 40)
        - Memos and budget statements, 1973-1976 (Box 40)
        - Summer Institute Reports, 1974-1977 (Box 40)
        - Wolff's Overseas Indonesian program, 1972-1977 (Box 40)
      - Thailand-Laos-Cambodia Studies Group
        - Ad Hoc Cambodia Group, 1973 (Box 40)
        - Correspondence, (scattered) (Box 40)
        - Newsletter (Khosana), 1976-1979 (Box 40)
        - Reports, 1975-1980 (Box 40)
      - Philippines Studies Group
        - Correspondence
          - 1972 (Box 40)
          - 1973-1974 (Box 40)
          - 1974-1975 (Box 40)
          - 1975-1977 (Box 40)
        - Newsletter, 1974-1981 (Box 40)
      - Translations Project Group
        - Correspondence
          - 1970-1973 (Box 40)
          - 1976-1977 (Box 40)
        - Reports, 1969 (Box 40)
        - SEARC, 1972-1980 (Box 40)
      - Vietnam Studies Coordinating Group
        - Book project, 1978 (Box 40)
        - Correspondence, 1970-1977 and scattered; 4 folders (Box 40)
        - Controversy over Southern Illinois University, circa 1970 (Box 41)
          - Correspondence and reports (Box 41)
          - Reports (Box 41)
        - Correspondence and reports, 1971-1980 (Box 41)
        - Newsletters, 1976-1977 (Box 41)
        - Saigon Prisoners issue, 1971-1974 (Box 41)